https://www.cognatebioservices.com/privacy-policy

OVERVIEW
Cognate BioServices is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy rights. This Privacy Policy, which applies when you use our website www.cognatebioservices.com, or otherwise use our services or interact with us, provides you with information about:
what data we collect;
how we use that data;
disclosures of your data to third parties; and
the legal bases on which we rely on to process your data.
You do not need to take any action as a result of this Privacy Policy, but you may have certain legal rights as described below.
It is important that you read this Privacy Policy together with any other privacy notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This Privacy Policy supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.
This Privacy Policy is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below:
Important information and who we are
The data that we collect about you
How we obtain your data
How we use your data
How we share your data
Data security
Data retention
International transfers of your data
Your data rights
Cookies
1. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE
Who we are
Cognate BioServices, Inc. (referred to in this Privacy Policy as “Cognate, “we”, “us” and “our”) is the “data controller” of your data. In simple terms, this means that we: (i) collect and make decisions about your data and (ii) make certain decisions on how to use and protect your data, but only to the extent that we have informed you about the use or are otherwise permitted by law.
How to contact us or make complaints
If you have any concerns or questions regarding our data protection practices (including any requests to exercise your data rights) or this Privacy Policy please contact privacy@cognatebioservices.com.
Though you have the right to make a complaint at any time to the competent data protection supervisory authority in your jurisdiction, we always appreciate the opportunity to address your concerns before you approach any such authority, so please contact us in the first instance.
Changes to this privacy policy and your data
This Privacy Policy is regularly reviewed and updated. We may amend or update our Privacy Policy from time to time due to changes in our practices, services, or legal requirements. We will provide you notice of amendments to this Privacy Policy and update the “last updated” date.
It is important that the data we hold about you is accurate and up-to-date. Please keep us informed if your data changes during your relationship with us.
2. THE DATA THAT WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU
We collect your data when you contact or interact with us, including on this website and as part of our provision of services, to carry out our business for the purposes set out below. The data we collect may include your name, address, email address, phone number, company name, and job title. We may also collect data through the use of cookies and similar technologies, such as your IP address, time zone, operating system, and device or browser information. See Section 10 ‘Cookies’ for more information about the data collected through our use of cookies.
3. HOW WE OBTAIN YOUR DATA
Information you provide to us
We collect data about you directly that you provide to us, including when you interact with us via email, post, telephone, and website. This includes when you:
interact with us in the context of Cognate providing you products or services (or in relation to the potential provision of products or services);
contact us via forms on the website;
request marketing materials to be sent to you;
provide us with feedback; or
browse our website with relevant cookies enabled.
Information we obtain indirectly
We may sometimes collect data about you indirectly via our affiliates, third party partners, and others to supplement the data we have collected directly from you, and use such data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
4. HOW WE USE YOUR DATA
We will use your data for the following purposes, and pursuant to the corresponding legal bases:
Purpose
Purpose
To enter into, and perform, contracts with you that you have requested, such as the provision of our services to you; including communicating with you in relation to the performance of such contracts; and processing payments for the services we provide.
Performance of a contract with you
To manage our relationship with you, including notifying you about changes to our terms or this privacy policy, or asking you to leave us a review.
(a) Performance of a contract with you(a) Performance of a contract with you(c) Legitimate interests
To keep a record of your relationship and history with us or our affiliates.
(a) Compliance with a legal obligation(b) Legitimate interests
To analyse and improve our website, products, services, marketing and customer experiences; troubleshoot the services and secure the services; and provide customer service
Legitimate interests
To provide you with relevant content and advertisements when browsing our website, and to understand the effectiveness of advertising that is presented to you.
(a) Legitimate interests(b) Consent
To provide you with recommendations about our or our affiliates products or services that may be of interest to you.
(a) Legitimate interests(b) Consent
Please note that we may process your data for more than one lawful basis depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data.
Marketing
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have you provide your consent, or if we have another lawful basis on which to send these communications to you.
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us at privacy@cognatebioservices.com or by following the unsubscribe instructions in the communications. We will comply with your request in accordance with our legal obligations. Please note that we may continue to send you non-marketing communications, such as legal notices, information about your orders, or important services updates.
5. HOW WE SHARE YOUR DATA
We will disclose your data to third parties if required to do so by law or regulation. We will also share your data with the following parties for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy:
(i)
certain third-party suppliers and service providers (including payment card processing, sales, marketing, analytics, research, security, legal and professional services, and data storage services), who assist in providing services to you on our behalf;
(ii)
our affiliates, which are entities under common ownership or control; and
(iii)
third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If such a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your data in the same way as set out in this Privacy Policy.
6. DATA SECURITY
We have put in place a variety of physical, administrative, and technical security measures to prevent your data from being accidentally lost, used, disclosed, or accessed in an unauthorised way.
We limit access to your data to those employees, agents, contractors, and other third parties who have a business need for such access. These individuals are also subject to a duty of confidentiality.
7. DATA RETENTION
We will retain your data only for so long as we need it for the purposes it was collected, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements, unless a longer retention period is required under applicable law or requested by you.
To determine the appropriate retention period, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of the data, the purposes for which we process your data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
In some circumstances we may anonymise or de-identify your data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use and share this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
8. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF YOUR DATA
We may transfer your data to countries located outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) where a third party identified in Section 5 ‘How We Share Your Data’ is located outside of the EEA. Where such transfers take place, they are made in accordance with applicable data privacy laws, such as through EEA-approved standard contractual clauses and other mechanisms.
9. YOUR DATA RIGHTS
Depending on the laws of the jurisdiction in which you reside (such as in the EEA), you may have various rights with respect to your data. . These rights may consist of the following:
provide access to and/or a copy of certain data we hold about you
update or rectify data which is out or data or incorrect
delete certain data which we are holding about you
oppose, cancel, or restrict the way that we process and disclose certain information
transfer your information to a third-party provider of services
revoke your consent for the processing of your information
We will consider all requests and provide our response within the time period stated by applicable law. Please note, however, that certain data may be exempt from such requests in some circumstances, which may include if we need to keep processing your data for our legitimate interests or to comply with a legal obligation. We may request you provide us with information necessary to confirm your identity before responding to your request as required or permitted by applicable law.
10. COOKIES
Our website uses cookies and similar technologies. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers stored on a browser when you visit a website that provides information about how you interact with a website. We use cookies to improve your website experience, provide additional security, analyse use of the services and remember you when you return to the website. Sometimes, these cookies are set by third party analytics providers, such as Google Analytics.
You can change your browser settings to warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off or disable certain cookies. Each browser is different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookie settings. To opt out of Google Analytics, please click here.
To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.aboutcookies.org.
We have outlined the details of the specific cookies used on this website in the table below:
Cookie name
Source
Purpose
Duration
Information provided to third parties?
_gat
Cognate
Used to throttle user requests
1 day
Yes (Google)
_gid
Cognate
Used to track visitor behaviour
1 day
Yes (Google)
_ga
Cognate
Generates statistical data on how visitors use our website
2 years
Yes (Google)
NID
Google Analytics
Stores a temporary unique identifier for your session to remember your preferences
6 months
Yes (Google)
